mathtag.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy Policy - MediaMath

Last Updated: December 31, 2019

### Introduction

Welcome to MediaMath’s Privacy Policy (“ **Policy** ”). In this Policy, we use the terms “ **MediaMath** “, “ **our** “, “ **us** ” and “ **we** ” to refer to MediaMath, Inc. and our affiliates.

MediaMath is committed to protecting the privacy of individuals (“ **users** ”, “ **you** “, “ **your** “) when we process data about them via our proprietary TerminalOne™ platform (the " **Platform** "), when they visit our website at www.mediamath.com (the " **Website** ") and when we engage in marketing activities based on contact information they provide to MediaMath through other means described in this Policy.

This Policy is provided in a layered format, so you can click through to the specific sections that may interest you.

### 1\. Important information and who we are

__Purposes of this Policy__

This Policy sets out how MediaMath collects and processes personal data, personal information or the equivalent terminology in your jurisdiction (" **personal data** " or " **personal information** ") about you via the Platform, when you visit the Website, and when we engage in marketing activities based on contact information you provide to MediaMath through other means described in this Policy. It also sets out our practices regarding our use of such personal data, the steps we take to protect it, the parties to whom we disclose it, and the choices and rights that you have regarding how we collect and process personal data about you.

You should read this Policy carefully so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your personal data.

__Who we are__

MediaMath is a global provider of digital advertising media and data management technology. We provide a technology platform and services which help advertisers do a more effective job of reaching their desired audiences. This technology delivers greater performance, transparency, and control to advertisers and a better Internet experience to users. Our Demand-Side Platform enables our clients, including advertisers and advertising agencies, to purchase advertising inventory, including display, video, audio, social, native, digital out-of-home (e.g., billboards or ads you may see in taxis or buses) and mobile ads, from publishers in an automated fashion. Our Data Management Platform provides our clients with tools to onboard, segment, activate, and understand their data.

When MediaMath processes your personal data as a controller in the context of operating the Platform, the Website and our marketing activities, the controller of your personal data is MediaMath, Inc. If our clients have contracted with MediaMath GmbH, both MediaMath, Inc. and MediaMath GmBH are controllers of your personal data. 

MediaMath is an active member of the industry associations that govern policies around user privacy in the context of digital advertising, including at the time this Policy was written: the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI"); the Digital Advertising Alliance ("DAA"), the DAA Canada, and the European Interactive DAA; the Interactive Advertising Bureau in the US, Europe and various countries around the world; and the Association of National Advertisers. MediaMath complies with the "NAI Code of Conduct", the DAA "Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising", and their "Application of Self-Regulatory Principles to the Mobile Environment". We believe that these programs’ principles help protect user privacy. 

__How to contact us__

If you have any questions about this Policy, including any request to exercise your legal rights, and/or you have a disability which prevents you from electronically accessing this Policy and require it to be provided in alternative format, please contact us as follows.

  * If you are located in the United States or any other country outside of the European Economic Area (" **EEA** "): 
    * By email to [privacy@mediamath.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com)
    * By post to MediaMath, Inc., Attn: Alice Lincoln, 4 World Trade Center, 45th Floor, New York, NY 10007.
    * If you are a California resident inquiring about the California Consumer Privacy Act (" **CCPA** "), please contact us by one of the methods above, or by calling our CCPA Helpline, toll free at 1-844-966-4636. 
  * If you are located in the EEA, you may contact our data protection officer Melinda Clemans who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this Policy: 
    * By email to [privacy@mediamath.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com)
    * By post to MediaMath UK Ltd, Attn: Melinda Clemans, 230 Blackfriars Road, London, SE1 8NW

You have the right to lodge any complaints you have regarding our processing of your personal data with a regulatory authority. We care about your privacy, and we appreciate the chance to address your concerns before you do so.

__Changes to the Policy__

From time to time, MediaMath may revise this Policy. The date of the last update can be found at the top of the Policy, and this policy describes how we have handled personal data in the twelve months prior to the date indicated. If we make revisions that materially change or affect whether or how we collect or use personal data, we will notify you by email (if, as a user of our Website or recipient of our marketing communications, you have provided us your email address) or by means of a notice on our Website prior to the change becoming effective. If you would like to stay up-to-date on our most current policies and practices, you should periodically review this Policy.

__Personal data pertaining to children__

MediaMath’s products and services are not designed for children, the definition of which varies by jurisdiction, and we do not knowingly collect personal data from or about children. If we are made aware that we have received personal data from or about a child, we will use reasonable efforts to remove that data from our records.

__Links, other websites and other third parties__

This Policy relates solely to the personal data we collect and process about you in relation to our Platform, our Website, and other interactions you may have with MediaMath that are described in this Policy. MediaMath’s Website contains links to other sites, and the ads delivered by the Platform may run on a variety of other sites. Clicking on those links, accessing other sites, or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. MediaMath does not control these third-party sites and is not responsible for the privacy practices of such sites. You should refer to the privacy statements of such third-party sites to find out how they collect and use your personal data. Also, as explained below in Section 5, third parties may process personal data from you when you visit the Website. Such processing is governed by the privacy statements of such third parties.

### 2\. The personal data collected via the Platform

While MediaMath collects certain categories of personal data in the course of delivering an ad to you via the Platform, we do not intentionally collect directly identifiable data such as your name, home address, phone number, or any government identifiers such as your Social Security Number unless you provide such data in connection with any request that you may choose to make directly to MediaMath. Instead, MediaMath collects certain personal data related to your computer or device through the use of cookies and other similar technologies, as explained below.

We may assign a unique identifier called a MediaMath ID to your browser, your devices, such as your mobile device, connected television, or over-the-top television devices (" **OTT TV Device** "), or other screens you may encounter when we serve an ad to it or when you use it to access a client’s digital properties. Digital Properties include websites, emails, apps (" **Digital Properties** "). The MediaMath ID enables the Platform to determine within a reasonable level of confidence that a browser or devices is the same one with which the Platform has previously interacted. For example, the MediaMath ID allows us to determine that a browser or device to which we served an ad on Monday is likely to be the same browser or device for which we observed a purchase on Tuesday. In some cases, based on data we receive from our clients or partners, we are able to infer within a reasonable probability that a particular browser or device should be associated with the same MediaMath ID. Where we are able to associate more than one browser or device with the same MediaMath ID, we may use this information to deliver targeted ads across multiple browsers or devices. This is sometimes referred to as cross-device advertising.

The MediaMath ID can be a cookie ID (a unique ID assigned randomly by MediaMath to an unrecognized browser), a mobile advertising ID (a unique ID assigned by the mobile operating system, e.g. Apple ID for Advertising or Android Advertising ID), or an OTT TV Device Identifier for Advertising (a unique ID assigned by an OTT TV provider, e.g., Roku ID for Advertising)). 

Your MediaMath ID is personal data and is associated with other categories of personal data that we collect about you. These categories include the following:

  * **Bid Request Data and Impression Data:** MediaMath receives personal data about you when we have the opportunity to show you an ad on Digital Properties and collects additional data when we deliver an ad. We refer to this data as Bid Request Data and Impression Data. The sources of Bid Request and Impression Data are your browser or device and media supply sources, such as publishers (i.e. organizations who operate Digital Properties) and exchanges or supply-side platforms who display ads on publishers' Digital Properties. This includes data that may be considered personal data in your jurisdiction such as your Internet Protocol (“ **IP** ”) address, imprecise location (e.g., country, region, postal or zip code), browser type (e.g., Chrome or Internet Explorer); operating system (e.g., Mac OS or Windows); browser language (e.g., English or Spanish); and Internet Service Provider (e.g., Comcast or Verizon). It also may include IDs that our partners assign to your browser or device. 
  * **Pixel Data and Other Client Data:** MediaMath clients may import personal data to the Platform regarding your interactions with them when you visit their Digital Properties. We may similarly collect personal data when you visit our Website. This includes data that may be considered personal data in your jurisdiction such as the time you visited the site, the page URL, your IP address, your browser type (e.g., Chrome or Internet Explorer), the operating system (e.g., Mac OS or Windows), the type of device you used (e.g. laptop or desktop), and data regarding your activities on the Digital Properties. For example, if you are shopping online for a product, place a product in your online shopping cart, or make an online purchase, the client associated with the website or app may use the Platform to collect that personal data and later show you an ad on a different site or app related to that product. MediaMath clients also may use the Platform to collect hashed personal data that does not reveal your direct identity, such as hashed email addresses. The process of hashing is commonly used in digital advertising to convert directly identifiable personal data to pseudonymous personal data. We refer to everything described above as Pixel Data. Clients also may import personal data that they have obtained outside of the Platform, such as segments that our clients create or obtain independently from third-party sources. A segment is a grouping of individuals who share one or more attributes (e.g., “car enthusiast”). These individuals are identified by an online identifier in these segments but are not identified by name or other personal data that directly reveals their identity. Clients also may import personal data that they collect or independently obtain offline, such as personal data regarding a purchase you made in the client’s store. The client’s offline data is first processed by the client or a third party, which removes any directly identifiable personal data, appends a MediaMath ID, and transmits the file to MediaMath for processing. We refer to this data as Other Client Data.
  * **Third-Party Segment Data and Other Third-Party Data:** We work with audience providers who create and provide us with segments for us and our clients to use for advertising purposes. We refer to this as Third-Party Segment Data. We also receive personal data from third-party partners that allows them and/or us to associate the MediaMath ID with those partners’ identifiers (through a process called “cookie syncing”) as well as personal data that associates your different devices with each other. Certain third parties may provide personal data to us regarding video content that you view on television. We refer to this personal data in the Policy as Other Third-Party Data.
  * **Special or Sensitive Categories of Personal Data:** We do not knowingly collect any special categories of personal data about individuals in the EEA, including: personal data revealing your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership; personal data concerning your health, sex life, or sexual orientation; and genetic or biometric data. MediaMath also does not knowingly collect any data about other sensitive categories such as personal data about children, financial account numbers, insurance plan numbers, and criminal convictions or offenses.

### 3\. How we collect personal data via the Platform

The Platform uses various technologies to collect your personal data.

__Personal data we collect from your browser or device__

Like most digital marketing platforms, MediaMath uses cookies and other technologies to recognize browsers and devices and collect the categories of personal data described above in Section 2 so that we and our clients can infer your interests, deliver more relevant advertising to you, measure the impact of that advertising, and better understand your digital media usage patterns.

The types of technologies used via the Platform that enable us to identify a computer or device, and enable the Platform to function and serve more relevant ads include:

  * **Cookies** – Cookies are small text files. MediaMath uses cookies to uniquely identify an Internet browser. Certain browsers or browser settings sometimes block cookies or prevent them from working effectively.
  * **Pixels** – Pixels are transparent images, iFrames, JavaScript or mobile SDKs that we, our clients, and our partners use to understand how users interact with their Digital Properties.

__Personal data we collect from third parties__

As described above, we receive personal data from third parties such as our clients and partners, including audience data partners, media supply sources, and exchanges or supply-side platforms. We receive this personal data in a number of ways, including through server-to-server transfers, a process called “cookie syncing” and other client and partner calls to MediaMath originating from the browser. We process all of this personal data in the Platform.

### 4\. How the Platform uses personal data

We use the personal data in the Platform to deliver more relevant ads to you on behalf of our clients. We also use the personal data to improve our Platform and the products and services that we provide to our clients and partners, as well as to create new products and services. Below, we have set out a description of specific ways we use various combinations of your personal data in the Platform.

Personal Data Type | Purpose/Activity  
---|---  
  
  * MediaMath ID
  * Bid Request and Impression Data
  * Pixel Data and Other Client Data
  * Third-Party Segment Data and Other Third-Party Data

| 

  * Enabling MediaMath clients to create marketing campaigns;
  * Creating segments; 
  * Facilitating MediaMath clients’ creation of segments;
  * Making decisions related to the opportunity to display an ad (e.g., deciding which clients’ campaigns are a good match for a bid opportunity and what price to bid in each case) and placing the bid;
  * Setting, reading and modifying a MediaMath cookie or reading a mobile advertising identifier or OTT TV Device Identifier for Advertising;
  * Collecting information about a browser or device;
  * Facilitating our partners’ collection of personal data, including by placing partners’ pixels or tags on our clients’ Digital Properties;
  * Delivering ads based on your inferred interests or activities on Digital Properties;
  * Measuring the effectiveness of those ads and attributing your activities to our clients’ campaigns;
  * Generating and providing to clients reports and user-level data related to their campaigns in the Platform;
  * Automated decision-making and profiling based on personal preferences, interests, behavior, or location; 
  * Transferring data to a third party where clients have elected to use its services or where MediaMath has engaged a subcontractor to provide certain functionality or capabilities as a part of the Platform or to improve our Platform and the products and services that we provide to our clients and partners; and
  * Fraud detection and prevention.

  * MediaMath ID
  * Impression Data
  * Pixel Data
  * Other Third-Party Data

| 

  * Synchronizing MediaMath cookie ID with third-party partners.

  * MediaMath ID
  * Impression Data
  * Third-Party Segment Data and Other Third-Party Data
  * Pixel Data and Other Client Data

| 

  * Associating multiple browsers and devices with each other;
  * Development, maintenance, and commercialization of MediaMath’s cross-device graph that associates your different devices with each other;
  * Append audience membership to Client’s first-party data.

  * Pixel Data and Other Client Data
  * Third-Party Segment Data and Other Third-Party Data
  * MediaMath ID

| 

  * Mapping data pixels to third-party segments.

  * MediaMath ID

| 

  * Honoring opt-out requests for users who have opted out.

  * Bid Request Data

| 

  * Enabling hyperlocal targeting of devices within a defined location.

__Segments__

As described above, a segment is a grouping of users who share one or more attributes. Where allowed by applicable data protection law and industry self-regulatory associations:

  * Our clients may use health-related segments about non-sensitive conditions such as an inferred interest in health and wellness or cough medicine and allergy medications. [Click here](https://www.mediamath.com/files/pdf/Health-Segments-for-Privacy-Policy-12_19_19.pdf) for a list of the standard health-related segments and a sample of custom health segments provided for use by clients in MediaMath’s Platform. 
  * Our clients may use segments based on political information or interests. [Click here](https://www.mediamath.com/files/pdf/Political-Segments-12_20_19.pdf) for a list of the standard political interest segments and a sample of custom political segments provided for use by clients in MediaMath’s Platform.

While MediaMath does not knowingly create segments that are based upon what we consider to be sensitive information (for example, we do not create segments of EEA users based on personal data considered to be sensitive in the EEA, such as personal data revealing your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, personal data concerning your health, sex life or sexual orientation, or genetic or biometric data), our clients may use the Platform to process some sensitive data (but excluding sensitive categories in the EEA), which may come from our clients’ Digital Properties or our partners. MediaMath may process segments based on demographic information such as race, gender and income range where such is information is not considered sensitive. We take steps designed to ensure that this is done in compliance with applicable laws and self-regulatory guidelines, including through our contracts and policies with our clients and partners, but our clients are responsible for this processing, and any queries should be directed to them.

__Automated decision-making and profiling__

The Platform uses proprietary algorithms to make decisions about whether or not to bid on opportunities to serve you ads and, if so, how much to bid. The ads you see are the result of client campaigns that specify how much to spend and on what basis to spend combined with the use of our algorithms. The ways in which we use algorithms to determine bid prices may be considered automated decision-making in certain jurisdictions. Additionally, these processes, in combination with client campaigns described below, may constitute profiling in certain jurisdictions.

As explained above, we assign a MediaMath ID to your browser or device. Using proprietary technology, we associate data that we collect about you with this MediaMath ID and create segments using inferred details about certain of your preferences, behaviors, and demographic information. Many of our clients’ campaigns rely on such segments. For example, if you are browsing a shoe retailer’s website on your mobile device, we may infer that you are interested in buying sneakers and associate that mobile device with a sneaker-buyer segment. If a client subsequently wants to advertise sneakers, the client may choose to target that segment across your devices. If MediaMath then receives an opportunity to show you an ad on your computer browser, which has been associated with your mobile device by our algorithm, MediaMath’s bidding technology will automatically decide whether to bid and if so what price to bid, based on the data and algorithms outlined above.

The automated processes that we use do not affect your legal rights (such as your right to vote, take legal action, or freely associate with others) or your ability to receive social benefits or obtain citizenship, nor do they have legal effects on you. Also, we do not knowingly process or make automated decisions about EEA users based on any data that falls into special categories in the EEA. As described below, you have the right to object to this automated decision-making at any time and you may have additional rights described in Section 11.

__Legal basis for processing__

Our legal basis under the GDPR for collecting and using the personal data described above will depend on the personal data concerned and the specific context in which we process it. However, we will normally collect personal data from you only where the processing is in our (or a third party's, such as our clients’) legitimate interests and not overridden by your rights, such as your right to opt out. If we collect and use your personal data in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), this interest will normally be to operate the Platform and serve you ads on behalf of our clients. We may have other legitimate interests and, if appropriate, we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal data, please contact us using the contact details provided under the “How to contact us” heading above.

__Sale of personal information__

For the purposes of the CCPA, MediaMath has sold all of the categories of personal information collected on the Platform for certain processing purposes in the past twelve months. If you are a California resident and want to exercise your right to opt out of the sale of your personal information, please see the instructions below in the section Opt out of sale for California residents.

__Opt-out and choice mechanisms__

 **Opt out of tailored advertising**

If you want to limit the data that MediaMath collects about you and want us to not target ads that are based on your interests to your browsers or devices, you may opt out from MediaMath tracking and tailored advertising at any time through one of the ways described below. **If you opt out, you will still see ads, but those ads are less likely to have anything to do with products or services you care about.** With tailored advertising, you receive ads and offers that are more likely to be useful to you.

Your opt-out is only applicable to the Platform and does not opt you out from platforms provided by third-party companies. However, you can opt out from both MediaMath and many third-party companies at once; to do so, please see “Other ways to opt out of tailored advertising” below. When you opt out, MediaMath will collect data from your browser, app, or device only as needed to honor your opt-out and for limited research and development purposes to improve our browser- and device-recognition technology, which also helps to improve our ability to honor your opt-out. When you opt out, MediaMath also stops targeting tailored advertising to the opted-out browser, app, or device.

If you use multiple browsers or devices and wish to limit the data that MediaMath collects and do not wish to receive MediaMath tailored advertising on any of them, you must opt out from each browser and device individually.

__Opt out of tailored advertising in a browser__

You may opt out if you are using a browser by clicking the “Click here to opt out” link below. Please note that if cookies are not enabled in your browser, including if third-party cookies are disabled, or if you use certain ad-blocking tools, our opt-out mechanism may not work properly. Please also note that deleting your cookies does not opt you out. **If you clear your cookies, or if you use a different browser or device, you will need to renew your opt-out choice.**

**Opt this browser out of tailored advertising (if using a browser)**

Your current opt-out status with MediaMath in this web browser is:

__Opt out of tailored advertising in the mobile application environment__

You may opt out in mobile app environments using the “AppChoices” mobile application, where applicable, which you can download to your mobile device from your App Store or via the DAA AppChoices page [here](http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices).

__Other ways to opt out of tailored advertising__

You may learn more about tailored advertising and opt out of tailored advertising from MediaMath and other online advertising companies that are also members of applicable self-regulatory organizations by visiting their opt-out links:

  * NAI (browser) – <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/>
  * DAA (browser) – <http://optout.aboutads.info/>
  * DAA Canada (browser) – <http://youradchoices.ca/choices>
  * European Interactive DAA (browser) – <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/>
  * DAA AppChoices page (mobile) – [http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices](http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices/)

__Other ways to limit ad tracking in the mobile and OTT TV device application environment__

You also may limit ad tracking in mobile app environments on your mobile device as well as on your OTT TV Device. For the most effective and up-to-date methods for doing so, you should consult instructions provided by those device manufacturers. The NAI provides additional information regarding opting out on mobile available [here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/mobile-choice) and TV streaming devices available [here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/internet-connected-tv-choices/).

Where MediaMath receives a signal to limit ad tracking, we will collect data from your device only as needed to honor your choice and for limited research and development purposes to improve our device-recognition technology, which also helps to improve our ability to honor your choice. Where MediaMath receives a signal to limit ad tracking, MediaMath also will not serve tailored advertising in the apps on your mobile device or OTT TV Device.

__Opt out of sale for California residents__

When advertising involves the sale of your personal information under the CCPA, you receive ads and offers that are more likely to be useful to you. If you want to stop MediaMath’s sale of your personal information under the CCPA, please take the following two steps:

  1. Opt out of tailored advertising by clicking below (if using a browser that is not already opted out). As mentioned above, opting out of tailored advertising will limit the data that MediaMath collects about you, and we will not target ads that are based on your interests to your browsers or devices: 

Your current opt-out status with MediaMath in this web browser is:

  2. Contact [privacy@mediamath.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com) to request deletion of your personal data.

If you follow the steps above, you will still see ads, but those ads are less likely to have anything to do with products or services you care about.

If you use multiple browsers or devices and do not wish for MediaMath to sell your personal information associated with any of them, you must follow the instructions above for each browser and device individually. To do this, you can visit this page on each of your other browsers or devices or reach out to MediaMath using any of the methods set forth below at Section 11. If you are an authorized agent, you can contact us using any of the same methods.

If you have questions about how to opt out or limit ad tracking, please contact us at [privacy@mediamath.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com).

### 5\. The personal data we collect via the Website or offline 

If you visit our Website or certain third-party marketing applications used by MediaMath or if you interact with MediaMath in other ways described below, MediaMath collects certain personal data from you when you choose to reveal it to us, and we may also automatically collect certain personal data. Third parties may collect personal data from you if you use certain features on the Website. The Website also may reflect certain personal data provided to us separately when you provide your consent for such display.

__Personal data you provide__

When you visit the Website, you may choose to provide your personal data to set up an account, request information such as a demonstration of our products, or send us questions. You also may choose to provide us with your personal data through sources other than the Website, including, for example when you register for or attend an event hosted by MediaMath. The personal data may include your name, email address, company, title, region, and information about your business such as industry, size, revenue, and address. You have the ability to provide additional information at your discretion.

You also may provide us with your personal data on the publicly accessible blogs on our Website. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal data from our blog or community forum, please contact us at [privacy@mediamath.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal data, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

We do not link the personal data described in this section with personal data that we may have about you in the Platform.

__Personal data we collect automatically__

As is true of most websites, we gather certain personal data automatically when content is displayed to you on the Website and we store it in log files. This includes data that may be considered personal data in your jurisdiction such as IP address, browser type, Internet Service Provider, referring and exit pages, operating system, date and time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this personal data stored in log files to other information we collect about you. 

We also automatically collect, and allow certain of our partners and subcontractors to automatically collect, personal data from you when you visit the Website. This is done using various technologies including cookies and pixels. Examples of subcontractors include video providers and email service providers. We classify the data that we collect from you on the Website using cookies and pixels as Pixel Data, which is described above in Section 3. Our partners and service providers also may collect personal data, may sync with additional third parties, and may allow third parties with whom they partner to set cookies on the Website. Please note, MediaMath does not control these partners and subcontractors. You should refer to the privacy statements of such parties to find out what personal data they collect, how they use cookies and how they interact with other third parties. For further information on the cookies and pixels we use on the Website, including a list of the partners and subcontractors described above, and how you can opt out, please see our [Cookie Notice](https://www.mediamath.com/cookie-notice/).

__Social media features and widgets__

The Website includes social media features that allow you to share news, events, and blog posts from the Website on platforms such as Facebook, Twitter, and LinkedIn or by email. These social media features are hosted by the third parties providing them, and your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policies of the company providing them, which you should read and ensure you understand.

__Testimonials__

We may display testimonials from satisfied clients on the Website in addition to other endorsements. We will obtain our client’s permission before we place these testimonials on the Website. If you are a client who wishes to update or delete your testimonial, please contact us at [privacy@mediamath.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com).

__Legal basis for processing__

Our legal basis under the GDPR for collecting and using the personal data described above in this Section 5 will depend on the personal data concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. However, we will normally collect personal data from you only where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your rights, such as your right to opt out, or where we have your consent to do so. If we collect and use your personal data in reliance on our legitimate interests, this interest will normally be to operate the Website, communicate with you, send you marketing communications (where we have your permission to do so, if such permission is required by applicable law), and show you ads on Digital Properties. We may have other legitimate interests and, if appropriate, we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

In some cases, we also may have a legal obligation to collect personal data from you. If we ask you to provide personal data to comply with a legal requirement, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal data is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal data).

Where we are required by applicable law to obtain your consent, for instance (in some cases) in order to send you marketing communications, we will do so, and in such cases the legal basis for our processing of personal data will be your consent.

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal data, please contact us using the contact details provided under the “How to contact us” heading above.

### 6\. How we use personal data collected via our Website 

__Personal data you provide__

When you provide your personal data to MediaMath on the Website or through other means described in this section, we may use the data for the following business and commercial purposes:

  * To respond to your inquiry;
  * To understand your business and offer you potential business opportunities;
  * To know or infer your interest in marketing products and services;
  * To enrich certain personal data you provide, for example your IP address or company information with information obtained from third parties;
  * To segment (group) you with similar individuals;
  * To provide you with information and offers about MediaMath products and services, information resources (e.g. whitepapers, reports and webinars), industry news and opinions, and announcements about MediaMath;
  * To inform you about and invite you to events, educational opportunities, or training opportunities;
  * To ask you to share MediaMath information, offers, and invitations with other people; and;
  * To attribute your responses or actions to specific marketing campaigns, activities, and channels.

You may choose to stop receiving marketing communications at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions included in any marketing communications we send you or by contacting us via email at [privacy@mediamath.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com).

__Personal data we collect automatically__

MediaMath uses information from the Website log files for troubleshooting and security purposes. We use the Pixel Data that we collect from you on the Website for the purposes described above in Section 4. Accordingly, each purpose and activity that applies to our clients in Section 4 could apply to MediaMath. For example, we may use Pixel Data that we collect from you on the Website to deliver ads to you when you visit other Digital Properties, and we may collect additional personal data from you on those Digital Properties, such as Bid Request Data or Impression Data. We use other data that is collected on the Website using cookies and pixels to determine how you found out about us, what your interests are regarding our services, and how to further improve the functionality of the Website and our service towards you as well as to analyze trends and administer the Website. For further information on the cookies and pixels we use on the Website and how you can opt out, please see our [Cookie Notice](https://www.mediamath.com/cookie-notice/).

### 7\. Disclosure of personal data from the Platform and Website

We disclose your personal data to the following categories of third parties for the business and commercial purposes set out above in Section 4 and Section 6:

  * We disclose the following categories of personal data to our affiliates in connection with our business operations that are based in our regional offices in the UK, Spain, France, Germany, Singapore, Brazil, Japan, Mexico and Australia: 
    * MediaMath ID
    * Pixel Data and Other Client Data
    * Bid Request and Impression Data, and
    * Third-Party Segment Data and Other Third-Party Data 
  * We disclose the following categories of personal data with our clients and resellers in connection with providing them with our digital advertising media and data management services and products: 
    * MediaMath ID
    * Pixel Data and Other Client Data
    * Bid Request and Impression Data
    * Third-Party Segment Data and Other Third-Party Data.
  * We also, at our clients’ direction, disclose their data to the third parties that they designate.
  * We disclose the following categories of personal data to our audience partners in connection with creating custom client segments based on client-supplied seed data or other data: 
    * MediaMath ID
    * Pixel Data and Other Client Data
    * Third-Party Segments
    * Impression Data
  * We also disclose the following categories of data with a limited number of audience partners in connection with audience creation or modeling: 
    * Bid Request Data
  * We disclose the following categories of personal data with our cookie sync partners in connection with synchronizing MediaMath cookie IDs with third-party partners’ IDs: 
    * MediaMath IDs
    * Pixel Data
    * Impression Data
    * Other Third-Party Data (specifically third-party IDs)

We work with a number of parties (referred to in this Policy as subcontractors) to whom we disclose personal data so that they can help us provide the services requested by our clients. These subcontractors provide the following services: measurement, viewability, location-based attribution and location-based targeting providers, dynamic creative optimization, attribution, fraud detection and prevention, providing mechanisms to honor user choices, infrastructure, storage, computing delivering content, analyzing supply inventory and reporting.

We disclose personal data to subcontractors who help with the operation of our Website, including services provided in connection with the Website including email services, event management, maintenance of our marketing database, web analytics, recruitment, management of marketing and customer relationship and social media.

We require third parties and subcontractors to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with applicable laws. We also define the permissible scope and, where appropriate, restrict the use by third parties of your personal data. We require our subcontractors to only use the information that we provide to them in connection with the services they perform for us and in accordance with our instructions.

We disclose personal data when we consider this to be necessary to establish or protect the legal rights of MediaMath or its employees, agents and contractors, as well as the legal rights of its clients or other third parties; to protect the safety and security of users and visitors to our Website; to protect against fraud; or to comply with the law or legal process.

We disclose personal data when we are required to or allowed to do so by law (for example in response to subpoenas, to comply with a binding court order, legal process, or government requests, including in response to a public authority to meet national security or law enforcement requirements).

If MediaMath negotiates to or sells all or part of its business or makes a sale or transfer of assets or is otherwise involved in a merger or business transfer, we may transfer or assign the personal data to a third party as part of any proposed or actual transaction.

We also may publish or otherwise make public anonymous, aggregate, or summary information regarding campaigns run in the Platform on behalf of our clients. For example, we may publish a report that reflects aggregated statistics regarding seasonal trends in shopping patterns or geographic differences in advertising impression opportunities.

### 8\. International transfers

The information that we collect from you and about you may be transferred to and stored in a country other than your country of residence, such as the United States, which may not offer the same level of protection of personal data as your country of residence. However, we will take contractual and/or other measures to ensure your personal data is protected.

__For individuals in the EEA__

MediaMath has its headquarters in the United States and many of our partners or vendors are based outside of the EEA. Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure that it receives a similar degree of protection by implementing at least one of the following:

  * Reliance on our or our applicable partners’ or vendors’ Privacy Shield certification if the transfer is to the United States.
  * Entering into contracts approved by the European Commission with our group companies and applicable partners or vendors.

__EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield__

MediaMath, Inc. complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss–U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data transferred from the EU and Switzerland to the United States, respectively.

MediaMath, Inc. has certified to the Department of Commerce that for all personal data it receives from the EU and Switzerland, it will adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfers, Security, Data Integrity & Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability.

If there is any conflict between the terms in this Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To find out more about the Privacy Shield, access the Privacy Shield List, and find details of our certification, please visit: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>.

Under the Privacy Shield, MediaMath, Inc. may remain liable if its subcontrators process your personal data in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, unless we prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

Residents of the EU or Switzerland who believe that their personal data has not been processed in compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles may raise their complaint in the following ways:

  1. You can contact MediaMath, Inc. directly using the details in the "How to contact us" section above. We will respond to your complaint within 45 days of receipt.
  2. 2\. We have further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield via the Better Business Bureau (“ **[BBB](https://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/)** ”), an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive a timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by us, please <https://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/> for more information and to file a complaint directly with the BBB.
  3. Further, your complaint can be made or referred to the U.S. Department of Commerce or the Federal Trade Commission for further investigation.
  4. For residual disputes that cannot be resolved by the methods above, you may be able to invoke a binding arbitration process under certain conditions. To find out more about the Privacy Shield’s binding arbitration scheme, please see: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>.

The Federal Trade Commission has investigation and enforcement authority over our compliance with the Privacy Shield.

### 9\. Data security and integrity

MediaMath implements appropriate technical and organizational measures to safeguard personal data in our possession against being accidentally lost, used, or accessed in an unauthorized way, altered, or disclosed. No transmission of data over the Internet, however, is guaranteed to be completely secure. It may be possible for third parties not under the control of MediaMath to intercept or access transmissions or communications unlawfully. While we strive to protect your personal data, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any data you transmit to us or that we collect about you. We have procedures in place to address any suspected personal data breach, and if we are required by law, we will notify you of any such breach. 

MediaMath processes information in a way that is compatible with and relevant for the purpose for which it was collected. To the extent necessary for those purposes, we take reasonable steps to ensure that any information in our care is accurate, complete, current, and reliable for its intended use. If you have any questions about security on the Website or through the Platform, you can contact us at [privacy@mediamath.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com).

### 10\. Data retention

__Retention of data collected on the platform__

As described above, we process your personal data for different purposes, and the length of time that we retain your personal data varies depending on the processing purpose, the category of personal data and certain external factors.

We will retain the MediaMath ID and, where applicable, its association with other devices for no longer than thirteen months from the last time we encountered that MediaMath ID on your browser or device.

We will retain all other categories of personal data that we collect or receive on the Platform, including Bid Request Data and Impression Data, Pixel Data and Other Client Data, and Third-Party Segment Data and Other Third-Party Data, for no longer than thirteen months, and we retain much of this data for shorter periods of time. Furthermore, we may delete personal data in response to a request from a user under applicable law, when requested to do so by our clients or when contracts with our clients end. Also, most cookies set via the Platform expire within thirteen months, while certain cookies that are not used for tracking are refreshed for as long as such cookies are necessary for our legitimate business purposes. 

__Retention of data collected on the Website and for marketing__

If you provide us with your personal data on our Website or through other means described above in Section 5, we will retain your information for as long as it is necessary for our legitimate business purposes. For example, if you sign up for an account or request information on the Website, we will retain the data you provide for as long as we think you may have an interest in receiving information from us. Similarly, we retain log files for as long as it is necessary for our legitimate business purposes.

We retain the Pixel Data that we collect as described above in the section "Retention of data collected on the Platform". 

### 11\. Your legal rights

MediaMath acknowledges that in some circumstances, you have certain rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. Depending on where you are located, these may include the right to access your personal data, correct certain personal data, erase your personal data, object to certain processing of your personal data, restrict certain processing of your personal data, receive personal data in portable format, and not be subject to decisions based solely on automated processing. To the extent required and permitted by applicable law, we will provide you access to the personal data we hold about you and also allow you to correct inaccurate information in certain situations (e.g., if you submit your email address on the Website), delete your personal data, object to processing, restrict certain processing of your personal data, port your personal data or elect not to be subject to decisions based solely on automated processing. 

If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please send your request to us at [privacy@mediamath.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com) and we will respond to your request in accordance with applicable laws.

In some circumstances, California residents have the following CCPA rights which can be exercised as follows:

Right to know about your personal information which we collect, use, disclose and/or sell  | 

  * Email [privacy@mediamath.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com)
  * Call us toll-free at 1-844-966-4636

---|---  
Right to delete personal information which we have collected from you  | 

  * Email [privacy@mediamath.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com)
  * Call us toll-free at 1-844-966-4636

Right to opt out of the sale of your personal information  | 

  * Email [privacy@mediamath.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com)
  * Follow the instructions above in the section “Opt out of sale for California residents”
  * Call us toll-free at 1-844-966-4636

Right not to receive discriminatory treatment for exercise of CCPA rights  |  MediaMath does not discriminate against you if you choose to exercise your CCPA rights.   
  
In order to process your request, we may need you to provide additional information to allow us to confirm your identity or the authority of any third party submitting the request on your behalf. We do this as a security precaution and to ensure that we do not disclose personal data to the wrong person.
